# LUIS BARRAGAN

Site: luisbarragan.co  $\diamond$  felipe.barragan@outlook.es  $\diamond$  (+57) 322 247 2062

#### **EDUCATION**

Santander Institute of Technology

Bachelor's degree, Systems Engineering.

Summa Cum Laude

January 2017 - March 2019

GPA: 4.72 on a 5.0 scale

Santander Institute of Technology

Advanced Diploma, Technology in IT Systems Development.

Cum Laude

January 2014 - March 2017 GPA: 4.59 on a 5.0 scale

## **PROFILE**

Summa Cum Laude Systems Engineer from Santander Institute of Technology (Unidades Tecnológicas de Santander). Team player with strong analytical and communication skills. Aptitude for learning and result oriented. He has been actively working in the design, development, and deployment of software products for different companies. Open to new career opportunities in the areas of Software Development, Data Analytics, and Machine Learning.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Final bachelor's degree project

HGASA UTS (Django Framework, Celery, Numpy, MySQL): Hybrid genetic algorithm with simulated annealing for solving the university course timetabling problem under an asynchronous task processing architecture and optimized fitness function evaluation.

## Final advanced diploma project

ReginarCMMS (Laravel Framework, PostgreSQL): Analysis, design, and development of a Computerized Maintenance Management System for the automotive fleet of Cootransmagdalena Ltd. in accordance with Colombia's National Road Safety Plan.

## Software project for Rambal S.A.S.

RambalQC (Laravel Framework, VueJS, OAuth2, MSSQL): Software for register and control the company's quality department formats and generate multiple reports (graphs and spreadsheets) about the registered data.

### Software project for Gescad S.A.S.

 $Herodot\ (Laravel\ Framework,\ jQuery,\ MySQL)$ : Software for storing client-related data and document retention policies in order to support their actual processes of interviews and retention, in accordance with the regulations of the General Archive of the Nation in Colombia.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Data Analysis

Programming Languages

Combinatorial Optimization

Databases
Deep Learning

Tools

Data Mining, DB Design, DB Modeling, ML

Python, Java, C#, PHP, JavaScript

Search algorithms, evolutionary algorithms, metaheuristics

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL, MongoDB

CNN, RNN, Computer Vision

PyTorch, OpenVINO, Django Framework, VueJS, GIT

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Rambal S.A.S., Giron

June 2019 - August 2019

Software Developer

· As a software developer for Rambal S.A.S., I built a stable version of RambalQC (v1.0).

# Rambal S.A.S., Giron

September 2018 - March 2019

 $Software\ Developer$ 

· As a software developer for Rambal S.A.S., during these few months I built the alpha version of the software RambalQC (i.e. Rambal Quality Control), managing the whole software development life cycle, for storing data inherent to the quality department and generating reports to support the decision making. Some of the implicit responsibilities were: to know the current situation of the company concerning quality controls and to propose software solutions to add value to the company, through interviews and constant feedback with the inspectors of the quality department.

## Gescad S.A.S., Bucaramanga

March 2018 - June 2019

Software Developer

· As a software developer for Gescad S.A.S. I built a software product for the company, managing the whole software development life cycle, for storing client-related data and document retention policies in order to support their actual processes of interviews and retentions, aligned with the regulations of the General Archive of the Nation in Colombia.

# Cootransmagdalena Ltd, Bucaramanga

January 2017 - August 2017

IT Engineer

· Collaborated in the deployment of new accounting software, as well as in the tasks of data integration with the old software. Participated in the company's quality certification process, as well as in the audits of the entities involved with the company's activities. Collaborated in the implementation of a new website and online ticket sales with different suppliers.

# Cootransmagdalena Ltd, Bucaramanga

August 2016 - December 2016

 $IT\ Intern$ 

· Person in charge of the IT department. IT resource management and operational support. Analysis, design, and development of a Computerized Maintenance Management System (ReginarCMMS) for the automotive fleet of the company, aligned with the National Road Safety Strategy of the Republic of Colombia.

#### Cootransmagdalena Ltd, Bucaramanga

February 2016 - May 2016

IT Assistant

· Person in charge of the IT department. IT resource management and operational support. The key responsibility was to ensure that the company's IT infrastructure is fully operational.

#### ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Received the Huawei Seeds For The Future Scholarship from June 18th to July 1st 2017 in Beijing and Shenzhen, China.

Participated as Speaker in the XIX National and XIII International Encounter of Research Seedbeds, held at the Simón Bolívar University in the city of Cúcuta, Colombia from October 13th to 16th, 2016.

Won First Prize in Programming Contest organized by Pontifical Bolivarian University, Bucaramanga in April 2013.

### HONORS AND AWARDS

Awarded with the Summa Cum Laude distinction as part of the Bachelor's degree in Systems Engineering. Bucaramanga, March 21st, 2019.

Awarded with the Cum Laude distinction as part of the Advanced Diploma on Technology in IT Systems Development. Bucaramanga, March 24th, 2017.

## MOOCS

IoT Fundamentals: Connecting Things

October 2018

Cisco Networking Academy

IoT Fundamentals: Big Data & Analytics

October 2018

Cisco Networking Academy

Introduction to IoT

July 2018

Cisco Networking Academy

Health Care IT: Challenges and Opportunities

February 2018

Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai through Coursera

Chinese for Beginners

September 2017

Peking University through Coursera

Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python

March 2015

MITx through edX

Entrepeneurship and ICT

December 2014

Telecentre Academy

## PERSONAL TRAITS

Self-starter, capable of taking initiative to identify and resolve problems.

Disruptive creative thinking, open-minded and cooperative.